delete all this and I can delete all
this here and now this is the full
function from before but it's just
really shortened up and to make this
even nicer we're not going to use var
and I change this to Const
just like in a normal function you can
pass arguments to arrow functions so let
me show you how to convert this function
into an arrow function so it's a normal
function now and it has two arguments
and then it's going to concatenate the
two arrays passed in so first we'll take
off the function keyword we're gonna
leave these parentheses with the
parameters now I'll put the arrow
since all we're doing is returning this
we don't even need the return keyword
and we don't need the curly braces so
I'll take that off we'll take this off
and now we've done this I just converted
that function into an arrow function and
it has these two parameters so we just
have the parameters and parentheses we
have the arrow and then we have what's
being returned right after the arrow so
if I run that you'll see that we
concatenate the two arrays that are
passed in in this example and then for
good measure we'll change this to
constant
arrow functions work really well with
higher-order functions such as map
filter and reduce I'll go into more
detail at a different time about map
filter and reduce but the main thing to
know is that they take functions as
arguments for processing collections of
data whenever one function takes another
function as an argument that's a good
time for an arrow function so what we're
going to do here is we're going to
update this function right here we want
to compute the square of only the
positive integers in the array so it's
passed in this array which is this and
we want to filter out everything that's
not a positive integer so I'm going to
use the filter and map functions to do
that but the main thing I want you to
look at is the arrow functions that I'm
passing in to filter a map this line is
going to be a lot more succinct because
of the arrow functions so we have the
squared integers is going to be the our
our and we're going to filter this so
dot filter now again I'm not really
gonna explain in detail what the filter
function does but that'll be something
for another time just look at this arrow
function we're gonna create this arrow
function am i starting it just like this
now before I showed you that you pass in
arguments in parentheses for an arrow
function but if you only have a single
argument like this the number argument
you don't need parentheses around the
argument you can just put the argument
and then the arrow so this is the
beginning of the arrow function and then
we'll see what's returned from the arrow
function first we want to filter this
array so we only have numbers that are
integers and numbers that are more than
0 so we'll do number that is integer and
then we will pass in the number and
number is more than 0 so let me complete
the parentheses here now the result of
this filter command will be an array
with all the numbers that are more than
zero and also integers so there'll be
442 and six but after we get that new
array we want to get the square of each
number in that array so that's where
we're going to use the map function now
the map function takes a function as its
argument but instead of writing a full
function out we can use an arrow
function so we're going to pass in X to
the function and there's gonna be an
arrow function now X just means every
element from the array that's being
passed to it
so remember the map is getting the array
for 42 6 X means for every element in
the array this is what we're gonna do to
it x times X because it's gonna be
squared again the main point of this
lesson is not to understand the filter
and math functions but to see that we
can put an arrow function we can pass in
an arrow function and it makes it so we
can fit everything really succinctly on
one line
so let's reload this and see if it works
now we have 16 1764 and 36
in order to create more flexible
functions you can use default parameters
the default parameter kicks in when the
argument is not specified or is
undefined so for instance with this
increment function we want to change it
we want to change the increment function
so you can pass in two arguments the
five and two to increment by 2 or you
can just pass in the 1 argument the 5 if
you want to increment by 1 so here the
numbers were passing in a number and a
value so we just have to put value
equals 1 so now if a value isn't passed
in it will be set to 1 automatically but
if it is passed in it will be set to
whatever is passed in so if we run this
we can look on the console we have 7 for
this first one and 6 for the second
the rest operator allows you to create a
function that takes a variable number of
arguments the rest operator is three
dots so we have this function here and
it's taking three arguments XY and Z and
it's summing them so at first it's
converting these XYZ into an array
called args and then it's reducing them
so it's summing them all up here and
then returning the result so right now
if we just run this it's going to log
six because one plus two plus three is
six but we can change this to use the
rest operator so we're still going to
pass in one two three but where it's
accepted here where we have the
arguments here XYZ I'm just gonna put
dot dot dot that's the rest operator
just dot dot dot and I'm going to put
args
so with this rest operator dot dot dot
it will convert everything that's passed
in into one array and the array is
called args so now we don't need this
anymore and it should work the same if
we run this we'll get six but we can
also now add any number of numbers so
I'll put a four on the end and ten it's
going to add those numbers together so
before we can only pass in three
arguments and now we can have any number
of arguments
the spread operator looks just like the
rest operator three dots but it expands
in already existing array or it spreads
out an array so it takes an array and
spreads out into its individual parts so
here we have an array with some months
and the spread operator can spread this
array that's our one into the individual
months instead of the actual array here
you can only use it in an argument to a
function or in an array of literal so
let's look at this so right now we're
setting array to two equal array one in
this example we're not actually copying
it because if we change array one if we
set the index of the array one two
potato and we log array two you'll see
that index zero is potato even though
we're logging array two and we only
change array one because these are equal
array two and array 1 are the same but
what if we want array to to be a copy of
array one we can use the spread operator
now we can't just use the spread
operator like this that's not gonna work
but if we put this inside brackets which
is an array it will spread out the
contents of array one into this new
array so we're not making array to equal
array one we are making array to equal
all of the contents of array one so
they'll be different so if we run this
again you'll see that it says January
for the first element and the array
instead of potato
the next few lessons will be about
destructuring assignment this is a
special syntax for neatly assigning
values taken directly from an object to
a variable so look at this object here
we have this object with three elements
we have the x y&amp;z with their values and
it's all in the voxel variable so if we
want to take each individual element in
this object and assign it to its own
variable this is the old way of doing it
so you could do Vox without X to stores
X voxel that Y stores Y voxels at Z the
store Z now with with destructuring
there's a simpler and quicker way to
assign variables for each element in an
object so here's the destructuring
syntax right here this time we are
creating various a b and c and assigning
them to the values from the object x y
and z we can see we put in curly braces
here and we just say it equals the
object it equals a voxel you can read it
like this get the feel of X and copy
into the value a so get the feel of X
from the object copy into the value a
get the feel of Y from the object copy
into the value B get the feel of Z copy
it into the value C so this is just a
quicker way of assigning things from an
object into variables now we're going to
use the structuring to obtain the
average temperature for tomorrow from
the info object average temperatures so
we have average temperatures it has
today and tomorrow's temperatures and
then the average temperature is inputted
into this function here so I'm going to
change this line here to use
destructuring
and the structure the average
temperatures object here that's passed
into this function so first I'm just
going to put the average temperatures
variable here and then on this side of
the equal sign I'm going to have to use
two destruct
shirring so I'll put the curly braces
and we'll put tomorrow and the colon and
then the other curly brace so this is
saying get the tomorrow field from the
average temperatures object and assign
it to the temp of tomorrow variable so
if we run this we should see it says 79
in the console because we got the tempo
tomorrow variable we return temp of
tomorrow and it was logged right here so
we successfully used the structuring to
get the tomorrow variable out of average
temperatures
we can also use the structuring
assignment to assign variables from
nested objects we have this nested
object right here the local forecast and
inside we have some nested objects so we
have the forecast from today and the
forecast from tomorrow so here we have
get max of tomorrow where we're going to
pass in the forecast and here we can see
the local forecast becomes the forecast
variable and we're trying to figure out