the number six to be added to the end of
the array so we'll just do our push and
then I'll put in num just like that
well actually it's item so what we did
we took this array that was passed down
here which is in this case test array
and we pushed the item that was passed
in and in this case here it's im6 now we
want to return the first item on the
list we want to remove
and return this item so that when we
council that log here it should show the
number one so instead of returning item
I'm gonna return our shift
that's what shift does shift removes the
first item and returns that first item
so let's check this out okay you can see
before one two three four five then
we've popped off the one and after it's
two three four five six we did it
boolean czar another data type in
JavaScript there are only two values
true or false they're basically little
on-off switches where true is on and
false is off
they don't use quotation marks around
the the boolean C it just says return
false so this is a function here it
should be indented where it's just going
to return false when you call this
function it could also be true so we
could return true you can use true and
false in more places than just function
returns and we'll be talking more about
that later
an if statement is used to make
decisions in code the keyword if tells
JavaScript to execute the code in the
curly braces under certain conditions
defined in the parentheses so here is a
full if statement right here and there's
always parentheses after the keyword if
and here is the condition so if the
stuff inside this print inside these
parentheses evaluates to true then the
code within these curly braces will be
evaluated or run so in this case it's a
variable so if the is it true variable
is true it will return yes it's true now
if it's is not true then we'll get to
the second return statement no it's
false so this whole function here takes
in a variable and we check if that's
true or not so I'm gonna make another
example just like this we have another
function that hasn't been filled out yet
true or false and there's a variable S
pass in was that true so we'll say if
and then the parentheses was that true
but that's true we're going to return
something it will be a string just like
before and the string is yes that was
true if it's not true then we'll get
this second return statement in the
function and we'll return a different
string will return no that was false
false
let me just add some semicolons and then
I can run this and we'll see what
happens
Oh returnees we spelled correctly so let
me spell return correctly so before I
run this I'm going to edit console dot
log here so we can console to log the
answer so this is the function call here
true or false we're passing in true and
then we're going to log what
returned here yes that was true since we
passed and true this if same evaluates a
true and this code is run right here
there are many comparison operators in
JavaScript that will return a boolean of
true or false the most common is the
Equality operator and it's often used in
an if statement so here it just says if
Val so we have this whole if statement
right here if Val we're gonna see if if
Val equals 12 now to check if it equals
12 we're gonna have to use the double
equal sign that is the Equality operator
and we'll say if Val equals 12 the
reason why we can't just use a single
equal sign is that a single equal sign
is the assignment operator if we just
had a single equal sign that would mean
that we were setting the value of the
Val variable to equal 12 we're not
trying to set this to equal 12
we're trying to check if the value of
this variable equals 12 so we have to
use the double equal sign so now this
test equal function is going to test to
see if the number we pass in is equal to
12 I can do a console that law here
console dot log and then we can see what
appears in the console here not equal
because 10 does not equal 12
we learned about the Equality operator
which is the double equal sign there's
also the strict equality operator the
triple equal sign so here we're checking
if 3 equals 3 with the strict equality
operator so the difference is that the
Equality operator the double equal sign
attempts to convert both values being
compared to a common type while the
strict equality operator does not do the
type conversion so this is going to
evaluate to true the 3 equals equals
equals 3 but the 3 equals equals equals
3 with the string on this side is going
to evaluate to false both of these would
be true if we were using the double
equal sign because the string would be
converted to a number and they would be
equal to true but with the triple equal
sign it does not get converted to a
number so it would be evaluate to false
the second one with the 3 equal signs so
here we're just going to use it right in
this if statement and who equals equals
equals 7 so now we can pass in the
number 7 and it's going to evaluate to
true but if we pass in a string 7 it
will evaluate to false
we will do one more review with the
Equality operator and the strict
equality operator so if I run this here
we'll see in the the console says equal
because it's checking if the number 10
and the string 10 are equal so if a
equals B the number 10 equals a strict
number 10 returned equal since we're
using the Equality operator with with
two equal signs it performs a type
conversion and it converts the string
into a number but if we use the strict
equality operator with three equal signs
I'll run that again and you'll see not
equal in the console because now it's
not converting the types and it's just
checking if a number is equal to a
string which is not so we get not equal
now I will show you the inequality
operator which is basically the opposite
of the Equality operator so I'm gonna do
the inequality operator with an
exclamation point in an equal sign in
this case I'm going to see if the value
is not equal to 99 and again just like
the Equality operator this does type
conversion so let's just run this
program and we'll see it is not equal
because 10 we pass them 10 into the
function here and 10 is not equal to 99
so we get not equal
the strict inequality operator is
basically the opposite of the strict
equality operator and works like this so
it says if Val I'm going to do if Val
does not equal 17 so this is the strict
inequality operator instead of one equal
sign we have two equal signs and that
means it's going to check if this is not
true but it's not going to convert types
so for instance if we are checking if
the number three does not equal the
string three that would be true so in
this example we're just checking if ten
does not equal 17 if we run this we will
see it's not equal
we can also use the greater than
operator so in this function we're
checking if a value is over 100 so I'm
going to put greater than 100 and then
here we're checking if a value is over
10 so I'll put greater than 10 so here
we call the function we pass in 10 and
if I run that function you'll see 10 or
under because we're not over 100 we're
not over 10 or 10 or under because we
passed in 10
we can also use the greater than or
equal to operator so we'll finish this
function by using greater than or equal
to that's just a greater than sign in an
equal sign and we'll put 20 down here
just greater than or equal to 10 if I
run that we should see 10 or over
because we're passing in 10 and it's
greater than or equal to 10
now I'll show you an example of the less
than operator with this function we're
going to check if the value is less than
25 and then here we're checking if a
value is less than 55 so here's a trick
I use to remember which symbol is less
than 1 which symbol is more than if you
see the less than symbol looks kind of
like the letter L which is the first
letter in less than and then the more
than symbol is just the opposite
and we also have the less than or equal
to operator we can use in JavaScript so
here we're going to check if it's less
than or equal to 12 so we just put the
less than operator 12 Oh evil less than
or equal that's an important part here
it's the less than or equal to 24 to
make this statement true and if we run
we see smaller than or equal to 12
number 10 we passed in
sometimes you want to check if two
things are true at the same time for
instance you may want to check if this
value is less than or equal to 50 and
you also want to check if the value is
more than or equal to 25 so we here we
have a nested if statement so it's going
to check if it's less than equal to 50
and if it's more than equal to 25 then
it's going to return yes but there's an
easier way to do this so what I'm going
to do is copy this where it says value
is more than or equal to 25 I'm going to
delete this nested if statement so we
don't need that if statement and I'm
going to use the and operator so we have
less than or equal to 50 and if I put
two ampersands like this that means and
now I'm going to put value is more than
or equal to 25 so this says if value is
less than or equal to 50 and the value
is also more than or equal to 25 then
we're going to return yes so both this
statement and this statement have to be
true to get into inside this if
statement here
in this code here we're checking if the
value is not between 10 and 20 so if the
value is less than 10 we return outside
and if the value is more than 20 we
return outside there is an easier way to
do this with the logical or operator so
I'm just going to delete this whole if
statement here and then I can add an or
statement which is just 2 pipes so I'm
going to put Val is less than or it more
than 20 here so now we're checking if
the value is less than 10 or if the
value is more than 20 either way we're
going to return outside and if that's
not true we'll return inside
when an if steam is true normally the
block of code right after the if
statement will be evaluated and if it's
not true nothing happens but with an
else statement an alternate block of
code can be executed when it's not true