the max of tomorrow so we are going to
use destructuring to figure that out so
it's going to equal forecast and
remember that is a nested object so here
when you're destructuring you're always
going to use the curly braces and we are
first going to get tomorrow and on the
other side of the colon we're gonna have
some more curly braces because it's
nested so we need to go inside of the
tomorrow object and we need the max so
we'll do max and then we have the colon
and max of tomorrow now we need two sets
of squiggly braces here so we have this
one and this one and so we've
destructured two times and the variable
is max of tomorrow so we've set the max
that was inside tomorrow to max of
tomorrow so if I run this you'll see
it's eighty four point six
you can use the structuring assignment
to assign variables from arrays look at
this example here so we have this array
of 1 2 3 4 5 6 and we're assigning the
variables Z and X to the first two
numbers of the array 1 &amp; 2 the
difference between destructuring from
arrays and destructuring from objects is
that you cannot specify which element
from the array to go into a variable it
just goes in order however if we wanted
number 4 to be going to a variable we
could just do like this we would just
add some commas so we put a comma with
nothing in it like that two commas in
row and I'll put a Y here so now we have
the first element the second element we
skip the third element and then we have
the fourth element so if I console that
log z x and y we should see one two and
four here's another thing you can do you
can use the structuring of arrays to
switch the places of variables let me
uncomment out these and what I'm going
to do is use the structuring to switch
the places of a and B so it'll be like
this I'll say a B and I'll say equals B
a so now it's just taking this and
switching the places so instead a being
8 and B equals 6
it's now gonna log out 6 and 8 so let's
see yep it worked
we can use this structuring assignment
with the rest operator to reassign array
elements we can see in this example we
have this array that digits 1 through 10
and the array and we have this remove
first to function we're calling it here
and we're passing in the source that's
the source array and becomes the list so
we want to return the array with the
first two elements removed so let's use
the rest operator inside an array here
so we'll use the rest operator the three
little dots and to remove the first two
I just have to put two commas here with
nothing in between them so it's saying
do nothing for the first element do
nothing for the second element
everything else put into the our
variable we could have assign the first
two numbers in the array to two other
variables so I could do a B and then a
would be one B would be two and then R
would be an array of three four five six
seven eight nine ten but right now we
just need to return the array with the
first two elements missing so if I run
that you'll see that we did that if you
look in the console we've logged the
array and the first two elements are
missing and then we have the original
array down here
you can use the structuring assignment
to pass an object as a functions
parameter let me show you what I mean
right now we have this half function and
it's getting the stats argument so the
stats is being passed when it's called
down here and it's passing in this whole
object so this whole stats object but
you can see within this function we're
only using stats that Max and stats top
men so instead of passing the entire
stats into this function we can just
pass in what we need so this is what
we're gonna do I'm going to put in some
curly braces here and just put Max and
min so now when stats get passed in it's
D structured into just the max and min
variables and the max and min from the
function gets passed in so now instead
of doing stats that max we can just do
max and sort of stats that men we can do
men so if we reload that it's gonna work
exactly like it did before but now we
only pass in what we need this is
commonly used with API calls when you
are getting information from an ajax
request or an api request it will often
have a lot more information that what
you need and you can use destructuring
to get it down to what we actually want
to work with
template literals are a special type of
string that makes creating complex
strings easier you make them with this
backtick so here's an example of a
template literal right here we have the
beginning back tick and we have the
ending back tick this would be in place
of using a quotation a single or double
quotation mark a few advantages of using
these template literals these back ticks
instead of quotation marks are one you
can make multi-line strings you can see
this has two lines here's the first line
and here's the second line and if we log
the greeting is gonna put the new line
right in there another thing is you can
add quote single or double quotation
marks right in the string and you don't
have to escape them the third thing is
you can put variables right in the
string so if we see this see the dollar
sign and then we have these curly braces
and so anything in between these curly
braces that start with the dollar sign
is JavaScript so right now we just have
this variable person name which gets the
name from up here and then here we have
person that age which gets the age from
right there so it makes things easier
that you can put variables right in the
strings so if we run that you'll see
hello my name is zodiac as bro I am 56
years old and normally it would actually
also be printed with a newline but with
this exact code editor and console it
doesn't show the newline so there's
gonna be a coding challenge that we're
gonna do right down here we have this
make list function and we want it to
create a list based on the array that's
passed in so when we call make list we
pass and result that failure wellhere's
results result dot failure is this array
here and we want it to return an array
that looks like this
each element in the array is a template
literal that has some HTML in it and
then it also has this no var
on top and lime break that comes right
from this array that's passed in so
let's use template literal so to create
that so instead of setting this to equal
null I'm going to start this off to be
an empty array now there's many ways to
do this but I'm gonna use the classic
for loop so we'll do four and hopefully
you remember how to make a for loop will
you let I equal 0 while I is less than
our dot length and then at the end we
will increment I so inside this for loop
will do result display array dot push
and then here is where I'm going to use
the template literal put a back kick and
I'll put this HTML code here li class
equals text warning and now this next
part is going to be a variable because
it changes for each array element here
so I'm gonna do dollar sign and then the
curly braces and now I can just do R and
then at index I now in the curly brace
and then I can just put the /l I okay
and if we console dot log this out
because we just finished that video
console dot log result to display array
the array looks just like it's supposed
to be if you look in the console it
returns correctly
es six added some nice support for
easily defining object literals if we
look at this function here this function
is an arrow function it takes in three
variables name age and gender and it's
going to return an object and the object
is going to have a series of key value
pairs where the key is
the name age and gender and the values
are the past in variable names the past
end names
age and gender so if you look in the
console you can see what this currently
does we did the create person we passed
a name age and gender and you can see in
the console the object is name and
zodiac as bro age 56 gender male so you
can see there's some repetition we're
repeating name name age age gender
gender now the first name is the key in
the second name is the value but there's
a way to just make this simpler if you
know that you want to create an object
with where the key is the name of the
variable and the value is the value of
the variable there's an easier way to do
it we can actually delete this whole
thing here and that's how we're gonna do
do it we'll just do name age gender on
the script knows that it's going to
return this object and it's going to
have three key value pairs the name age
and gender so if I reload this you'll
see in the console it looks exactly the
same because this code does the same
thing that the previous code did
an object can contain a function this is
the long way to put a function within an
object but there is a simpler way we
have the set gear function but instead
of using the function keyword and this
colon we can just delete all that and
now this is the new way if I load this
again you'll see three in the console
just like it was before because we've
been able to set the gear using that
function
yes six provides a syntax to help create
objects using the class keyword so
here's the older way to create an object
it's with the the new keyword we can
instantiate an object using this new
keyword and we're instantiating the
Space Shuttle object we have to have
this constructor function up here so we
use this to construct the object where
we pass in the target planet Jupiter and
we set the target plan to this dot
target planet once we create the new
object like this that allows us to do
Zeus dot target planet so Zeus target
planet which we set to Zuppa der Jupiter
so in the console you can see Jupiter
the class syntax replaces the
constructor function creation so I
believe that we're going to use the
class syntax so I'll do a class space
shuttle and then we have the curly brace
here and so inside here we have a
constructor so du constructor or get
planet and then that's all we just have
to put in the curly brace and this works
exactly the same as before using the
class keyword and this constructor so
down here we are going to do the same
thing for a vegetable class so for the
vegetable class we'll have class that's
the bowl and we're going to have a
constructor with the name this that name
equals name so now that we have this we
can set this vegetable to make class
which will return a vegetable class
that's up here and then when we do new
vegetable and passing carrot this carrot
will go into here and it'll get set as
this that name so when we console that
log here at that name
we should get carrot
with a class object you often want to
obtain values from the object and set a
value of a property within an object
these are often called getters and
setters so in this class object we have
the constructor which we already talked
about we also have a getter and setter
to get and set the writer so we can get
the writer and we can set the writer
getter functions are meant to simply
return or get the value of an object's
private variable to the user without the
user directly accessing the private
variable so the private variable is this
underscore author that gets set when you
construct the object and then when we do
get writer it's gonna return this down
underscore author so you never actually
interact directly with this variable but
it's going to get the writer which is
the author here and when you're setting
it's the same so you're never
interacting with underscore author but
you can set that with the writer setter
this change could invoke calculations or
even even overriding the previous value
completely so you can have any number of
code lines in this setter to ultimately
maybe do different calculations before
you set it or a calculation before you
get the property so what we're gonna do
is make your own getter and setter for
the thermostat class we're gonna create
a thermostat class and we're gonna have
a getter and setter so here's the thing
about this challenge is that when we
construct the class it's going to accept
Fahrenheit temperature but we're going
to create a getter and setter in the
class to obtain the temperature in
Celsius so it's gonna have to do the
calculation right within the class so
let's do that we're going to do a class
of thermostat and in this class we need
the constructor but when you first
create the thermostat you're going to
pass in a temperature and remember this
is going to be Fahrenheit now within
this constructor we're going to set a
private variable this dot underscore
temp so the word
this just means that this variable is
only accessible within this class here
and the underscore temp whenever you
start a variable with an underscore
that's going to generally signify that
it's a private variable that you're not
supposed to access it outside of that
scope or outside of that class so we're
gonna set the temp and we're not going
to just put this underscore temp equals
temp because it's passed in as a
Fahrenheit and we want to convert it to
Celsius I just happen to have the
equation for Celsius so it's five over
nine times and then with temp minus
thirty-two so now we can create the
getter and setter so we'll forget it
will you get temperature and we're just
going to return this dot underscore temp
which now it's in Celsius because we're
storing the value in Celsius even though
the thermostat is created in Fahrenheit
so with the setter it's going to be the
same set temperature updated temp and
it's now going to still be in Celsius so
this dot temp equals updated temp so
let's look at the code down here how
we're using it so the consular Mesilla
equals mate class this mate class
function is going to return this
thermostat object here and then we're
going to do a constant thermos equals
new thermostat so when you're
instantiating an object you always use
the new keyword new thermostat that's
this and we're passing in 76 that goes
into the constructor the temp and so we
do this calculation to convert that
Fahrenheit to the Celsius in this local
variable here and then let temp equals
thermal temperature
so thermostat temperature is going to
use the getter get temperature and it's
going to return this down underscore 10
so a key thing to look at is that there
are no parentheses after this so
generally if there's if something is a
function you would see parentheses after
the function name but if it's a variable
or property name it's going to not have
parentheses so getters and setters are
access similar to properties and then we
can use the setter here
thermostat temperature equals 26 and
then it sets it with the updated
temperature and now we can say temp
equals thermos temperature and if we do
a console dot log here we can do that
with the temp and it should have the new
temperature if I load that 26
in the past people would use the require
function to import functions and code
from other files but now we have import
and export you can export code in one
file and then import it in another file
it also allows you to only import
certain functions from a file or certain
variables let me show you how it works
so in this file we have this capitalized
string function we're passing in the
string hello and we want to log out the
capitalized strings but right now it
just has an error because there is no
capitalized string function in this file
however in this other file we do have a
capitalized string function in this
string function GJ s we have export this
is the export statement I was talking
about and then it's exporting this
function it's actually a variable
capitalized string that's set to equal a
function this is a an arrow function
where we pass in a string and then we
return the string dot to uppercase now a
to uppercase is just a string function
that makes every letter uppercase so we
can import this in our other file so
let's go back to our other file and I
will import and with the import
statement you're going to use curly
braces and then I'll put capitalized
string and then we have to say what
we're importing it from we want to
import it from and this is where I put
the file name now normally you're going
to start with a dot slash which just
means the current directory and I'll
type in the file name string function
now the file name is a dot a yes after
it but that's assumed so you don't have
to put yes you can just put the file
name without the extension so if I run
this you can see hello in all capital
letters is successfully imported this
function from the other file and we used
it in this file
I talked a little bit about export in
the last lesson but now I'm going to go
into more detail you export functions
and variables from one file so that you
can import them into another file that's
how you can reuse different code so we
have this function here this is a
capitalized string function it actually
just capitalizes the first letter of the
string and then leaves the rest of the
string lowercase and before I showed you
you can just put export right before
here but we can explore a different way
so I'll do export and then in curly
braces capitalized capitalized string
and so now we've just explored this
function and to export a variable like
this we have Constable's barkas
particles foo to export these variables
you just type an export like both before
so now in this file we're exporting this
function and these two variables and
then we could import them into another
file
if a file exports multiple different
things you can import each things
individually or you can import
everything so let me show you how you
would import everything from a file
it's just import and then you're going
to put an asterisk or a star and then
you're gonna put as import as and then
you have to create an object to store
everything in so I'm gonna import stuff
from a file called capitalized strings
so I'm going to call this capitalized
strings so this could really be anything
I'm creating an object with this and
then I'm going to say what I'm importing
it from from and then I just put the
file name in this case it's just going
to be capitalized strings sometimes you
would have to put a dot slash if it's in
the same directory there and then I'll
make sure to put a semicolon at the end
so if you're importing everything you
always start off with import star as and
then this can be anything it can be at
any object name that you create and
they're going to put from and then you
put the file name in quotation marks
just like that
before when I talked about exports I was
talking about named exports there's also
something called an export default this
is a fallback export and it's often used
if you only want to export one thing
from a file so if you let's say I want
this to be my fallback export I'm just
going to only export this one thing from
the file I can just put export default
so now we know that this is just the the
fallback though basically just the one
thing we're going to export from this
file
so we talked about exporting a default
export now I'm going to show you how to
import a default export it's pretty much
the same as before but there is a slight
difference so we are going to pretend we
have a file called math functions that
has a default export name subtract so
let me show you how you would import
that so it's going to be import subtract
and we've already reached the difference
here if it's not a default export you'll
put curly braces around this but it is a
default export so we are not going to
use curly braces but we still have to
say what it what it's from
so from math functions okay so that is
how you would import a default export
well thanks for watching don't forget to
subscribe and remember use your code for
good