so this is a perfect use case if value
is more than five the result is bigger
than five if there is if the value is
less than or equal to five the result is
five or smaller we can do this with an
else statement so I'm just going to type
in else here and then we can just delete
this whole if statement just like that
and now we have if the value is less
than five the results will be bigger
than five else if it's which is if it's
not more than five we'll return five or
smaller
if you have multiple conditions that
need to be addressed you can use else if
statements it's a way of chaining if
statements together in this example we
have three conditions if value is more
than 10 we're gonna return greater than
10 if it's less than 5 returns smaller
than 5 or else we're gonna return 5 and
up so this is a perfect use case for an
else if statement so this is how we do
it well do else and then just we're
going to add the if statement at the end
of the else I'm just gonna delete all
this stuff so else if value is less than
5 and then we're gonna have one final
else statement else and I'm going to put
this statement here this final return
just gonna cut that and then paste it
right in there so now we've instead of
using multiple if statements we have the
if and only the else if and then we have
the else
when you're using else if statements
order is very important let's look at
this example here in this function first
we check if the value is less than 10
and return less than 10 then else if we
check if the value is less than 5 and
return less than 5 well if we look at
this example when we pass in the number
7 if I run this you'll see it's going to
say less than 10 which is what we want
however if we put 3 it's still just
gonna say less than 10 really we want
this to say less than 5 because it is
actually less than 5
however the this is in the wrong order
so what we need to do is change the
order so this should be 5 this should be
5 and this should be 10 and this should
be 10 so once the first condition is met
it doesn't even check for the rest of
the conditions so that's why it's
important to think about the order so if
we run this now yep less than 5 that's
what we want
you can also chain if and else if
statements so I'm going to complete the
following challenge here right chained
if / else if statements to fulfill the
following conditions so we have these
conditions where if the number is less
than five we're gonna return tiny if
it's less than ten returns small and so
on so what I'm gonna do is actually just
copy this right here because this is
written as part of it's written exactly
how we want to be written I'll just
paste it here and I'm going to just add
the if and else statement so it's gonna
be if and then we put this in
parentheses because the condition is
always in parentheses if number is less
than five then we're going to use the
curly braces and we're going to return
tiny so I'll just move that up here I'll
cut it and paste it now we're going to
use an else if statement and I got the
curly braces
first of all also I need to put the
condition in these parentheses I'm just
going to cut this number is less than
ten put right here and we're gonna
return this small so I'll put that in
the curly braces here and then we have
another else if statement else if and
the condition just like before number is
less than fifteen but that in there we
get we always need the curly braces to
show what's going to happen in the if
statement so I'm just cutting and
pasting the text again we have an else
if and then we have this year and we
have return large another actually the
final thing is just going to be else we
don't even need an else if at the
statement at the end we're not we don't
even need to put the condition because
if it's more than equal to twenty that's
going to be everything else so I'm just
going to cut this we don't need any of
this stuff here and we're just going to
return
and large so with this one test here for
test seven we can actually cancel that
log that console dot log and see what
returns for seven we can try a few
different things
ooh we have an ear here oh forget to it
but this parenthesis wrong way let's try
that again
small but if this is 20 it should be
huge and if it's 19 which would be less
than 20 we should see you large yep that
worth
in the game of golf each hole has a par
which means the average number of
strokes you're supposed to use to get
the ball into the hole so depending on
how far above or below par your strokes
are there's a different nickname so here
are some of the nicknames hole-in-one
Eagle birdie par and we're gonna write a
function where you pass in the par and
you also pass on the stroke so you can
see up here par and strokes and it's
going to return the nickname so that's
what we're going to write you can see
this table here shows what we have to do
if the strokes are 1 then you get a
hole-in-one
if the stroke is less than or equal to
par minus 2 you get an eagle and so on
and we also have this array that's gonna
make it easier because we can you just
use things from this array instead of
typing out the words so we're going to
start with an if statement if and then
we have to put the condition if strokes
equals equals that's the Equality
operator we don't want to use a single
equal sign because that would be the
assignment operator if it equals 1 then
we can return and we can see down here
we're gonna return hole-in-one but we
can just use it from this names array so
it's going to be named and this is the
meet index 0 of the array so we'll do
names and then 0 and then we can do an
else if else if and then we can put the
condition strokes expel strokes right
spokes and then we can just actually
copy this right from here less than or
equal to power minus 2 and then we are
going to return name and this will be
the index 1 which is an eagle at this
point I can do some copying and pasting
I'm going to copy this whole thing's a
lot of this rest of this will be else if
so else if strokes is this time is going
to be equal
to par - one and we're going to return
this many birdie which is array index -
and I'm going to continue just like this
so this time it's if strokes equal par
we're going to return name index 3 C 0 1
2 3 is going to be the word par up here
they'll just keep just like this now
it's going to be R plus 1 and we'll
change this to 4 now it's going to be
par plus 2 and we'll change this to 5
which is gonna be the double bogey
and finally if strokes is change this to
more than or equal to car plus 3 that
means you did very poorly so you should
just go home so it's going to be named
index 6 and we don't need this anymore
so now we're gonna do some tests here
I'm gonna do a console console dot log
and we're going to pass in the function
that we're calling so in this case the
par is 5 and the strokes are 4 so that
should return birdie let's see what
happens
no ok that's not what I expected it's
because this should be names spelled
this wrong and that's why sometimes
better to check before you go through
the whole thing you can test things as
you go but let's do that again
yep birdie and if I type in 2 here eagle
if I
type and eat it's probably that tell us
to go home go home yep we just completed
this challenge
instead of using chained else if
statements you can use a switch
statement a switch statement test of
value and can have many case statements
which define various possible values so
let me show you how that works here
we're going to write a switch statement
which tests Val and sets the answer to
the following conditions if we pass in
one the answer should be alpha if we
pass on to the answer should be beta and
so on so let me show you how that works
we'll just type in the word switch
that's a key word here and we're testing
the valve that's passed into this
function so it starts off kind of like
an if statement and right now so we're
gonna compare the Val to the different
cases that we have so we'll have case
and the first number is going to be one
so here we're saying if the case of Val
is 1 if Val equals 1 and it's using the
strict equality operator so it's like
that equals equals equals it's going to
make sure that the type of the variable
are the same so a string 1 and a number
1 will not be equal but if the case is 1
then we're going to set answer to equal
alpha we'll just use the like this alpha
and then we are going to break break
means that we're at the end of that case
statement and once you break it it just
goes to the end of the switch statement
it doesn't evaluate anything else in the
switch statement so we're also going to
have case two and one thing I forgot
that we're gonna is going to end in that
so it's easier to see the different
cases and case 2 the answer is going to
set equal to beta and then we always
need the break statement if you don't
have a break statement it will just run
through to the next case statement
automatically so if the case was one and
you did not have a break here first who
would set the and
alpha and then it would set the answer
to beta it would just skip over right to
the next case Thema but since the break
is here it's going to go out of the
switch damn it completely so it would go
start writing the code after this last
curly bracket so now we're going to case
three we'll just do some copying and
pasting here and we're gonna have four
cases I'll just do the rest of the cop
the pasting here so we'll have three and
four alpha beta and then we have gamma
and Delta and we know that the switch
statement is over because we have this
final curly bracket and then we're just
going to return answer so let's do some
tests to really test this we're going to
have to add a console dot log here to
log what it's going to be and I'll run
this alpha good now two should be beta 3
should be gamma good and we'll just
assume for is correct
so we're done
now I'll talk to you about the default
option in a switch statement the default
option is kind of like else in an
if-else statement so here's a switch
statement that's very similar to the one
we already saw and it's inside this
function where we pass in a value into
the function and we're going to check if
the value equals a if it equals a the
answer is gonna be set to Apple B
intercept the birds see cat so in this
example we can see that we passed in
here we pass in a and it returned Apple
because that was one of the options but
what if we pass in something else if I
pass in the number two here it's going
to return an empty string that's because
the answer is set to an empty string and
we never override the answer here so it
just returns that empty string what if
we want to return something anytime a B
or C is not passed through so for
anything else that's passed into the
function we're gonna do default this is
like the else statement so the default
we're gonna do answer equals it's off
again we're gonna have the break so now
whenever we pass in something that's not
a B or C it's gonna return stuff so we
can pass in five it's gonna rain return
stuff but if I go back the pass again
see one of the things they have a case
for it'll return cat and that's the
switch statement
sometimes you want a switch statement
where multiple inputs give the same
output well that's easy enough by
omitting the break statement let me show
you how that works so let's get a switch
statement here and we're gonna have Val
that's what's passed into the function
and in this case when you want the case
of one two and three all to return the
answer of lo so I can do it like this
case one and I can go straight into case
two and then I can go straight into case
three and since I don't have any break
statement between these cases it will
just keep going to the next one
automatically and now I'm gonna say that
the answer is must be set to equal low
and here is where I put the break
statement okay now we're gonna do the
same thing with cases four through six
and actually I'm just going to do some
copying and pasting I'm gonna copy all
this and now we're going to paste that's
four five six we're gonna do the same
thing with seven eight nine so I'm gonna
do copy and paste again and then I'm
just going to update the code so this is
gonna be four five six we'll have seven
eight nine and we're gonna have mid and
high so if the case is one two or three
like for instance if it's one it's gonna
pass through two and three to get low
and then it's gonna break out if it's
four five or six it's gonna pass through
to get to mid and then it's gonna break
out seven eight nine it's gonna pass
through to high and break out so let's
test this out and see since we're
passing in the number one here it's
going to be low but if we pass in five
we should get mid and if it's seven
eight or nine
we should get high
sometimes a switch statement can be
easier to write and easier to understand
then a chain of if-else statements so
we're going to change this chain of else
if statements to become a switch
statement so let's do that right now
so I'm gonna start with the switch
keyword and we're going to be evaluating
the value with open curly braket and we
want to make sure to have an end curly
bracket end so for a case Bob we're
gonna set the answer to Marlee and then
we need to have a break in here for case
42 we're gonna set the answer to the
answer or case one whole set the answer
to there is no number one oh we need a
break up here for case 99 the answer is
miss by this much and then we need a
break now we have for case seven well
seven eight nine and break and now we
just changed that chain of else if
statements into a switch statement
here's a little trick when you want a
function to return a boolean a true or
false value you can see in this function
we're checking if a is less than B and
if so we return true else we return
false you may remember from before that
all comparison operators return a
boolean true or false value so instead
of using this if statement here we can
just do that we can actually delete all
of this and just return the result of
this return we're just returning the
result of a is less than B so this is
going to be true or false and we can
just skip that whole if statement logic
and just return this so if we consul
don't log this out console.log we should
be able to see if 10 is less than 15 it
is less than 15 it's true but if we put
a 20 here and it's false
we've already seen a few examples of
this but you can return early from a
function with the return statement so if
you see this this function right here we
return at the very end of the function
and so it leaves a function and returns
this value from the function but you can
leave the function anytime with a return
statement so we're going to modify this
function so that if a or b are less than
zero the function will immediately exit