equals a plus 12 we can do a plus equals
12 so this equals the same thing so
instead of B equals 9 plus B we can do B
plus equals 9 so now we're adding the
value to the variable and assigning the
answer to that variable so again here we
can do plus equal 7 so that's just a
shortcut
previously we learned about plus equals
well minus equals does the same thing
but subtracting so this says a equals a
minus 6 we started at 11 minus 6 is
going to be 5 so the new a is gonna be 5
but we can shorten that instead of a
equals a minus 6 we can do - equals this
is just a shortcut that JavaScript has
that means the same thing
that means a equals a minus 6 but it's
just shortened same here so we can do
minus equals 15 C equals C minus 1 we
can do C minus equals 1 so it just
subtracts the number from the original
value and then assigns that new value to
the variable
here we have a equals a times five well
we can do the same thing as before we
can shorten this to a x equals five so
that means the same thing here we can do
a x equals three and then C equals C
times ten we can shorten this to C times
equal 10 and that's another shortcut for
JavaScript
and there's also divide equal so a
equals a divided by 12 we can do a
divided by equal 12 and here we can just
do divided by equal 4 or divided by
equal 11 so another way of just dividing
the variable by a new number and
assigning that answer to the variable
we've already mentioned strings a little
bit but anytime you have some character
surrounded by quotation marks they can
either be single quotation marks double
quotation marks or backticks it's a
string these are called string literals
and you can create them just like you
see above I'm going to do a few more so
far my first aim equals bow and VAR my
last name equals Karns so that's how you
create a string in JavaScript
sometimes your strain contains the quote
symbol now normally the quotes identify
the beginning and the ending of the
string but what if you have something
like this I am a double quoted spring
inside double quotes so I'm actually
trying to use these quotes right inside
the string but the JavaScript doesn't
know what to do about it
it thinks that this is that it thinks
that this is the whole string when it
sees the first quote inside the string
it thinks R at the end of the string so
there's something called an escape
character so if you want to escape a
quote that means it will no longer be
considered the end of the string I'm
going to put a backslash so if I put a
backslash before each of these quotation
marks JavaScript no longer interprets it
as being the last character in the
string so now you can see this is a full
string and then if I log this out
console dot log and I put my string
you'll see that it's not going to show
the quotation marks so I mean it's not
going to show the slash the back slashes
it shows the quotation marks without the
back slashes because when we put
backslash quotation mark javascript
knows that this should just mean a
quotation mark
we talked about escaping a quote
character like this where you put a
backslash before the quote character so
javascript knows that this is supposed
to be a literal quote character inside
the string however you're not going to
have to escape quote characters very
often because there are other methods of
accomplishing the same thing of having a
quote character within a string so a
common way is to use instead of having
your strings start with double quotes
have it start with a single quote so a
string can either be surrounded by
single quotes or double quotes so this
time we're just going to have single
quotes and now I can remove all these
escape characters from inside the string
here okay so now you can see that
JavaScript still knows it knows that
this is a string even though it has
these double quotes inside an additional
thing you could do is use backticks so
if I put a back ticks before at the
beginning of the end of the string
now I actually can use single quotes and
double quotes both within the string but
right now I'm just gonna focus on
showing you the double quotes or the
single quotes with the double quotes
inside
we talked about escaping a double quote
character by using the backslash before
the double quote there's actually quite
a few other things you can escape out
you can escape out a single quote
character you can escape out a backslash
in fact anytime you're gonna use a
backslash you're gonna have to put two
backslashes so the JavaScript knows that
you're not trying to escape a character
you can also add a new line character or
a carriage return a tab a backspace or a
form feed all with doing a slash in the
corresponding letter here so let me show
you an example I'm going to put a var my
string equals and we're gonna make a
multi-line string so we're gonna have
the first line and now I'm going to put
backslash in to add a a second line and
then I'm going to put a tab so backslash
T for the tab and backslash backslash to
add a backslash now it's going to say
second line now I'll do backslash and
then I'll just say third line and if I
were able to log out all that you would
see three different lines and you would
see the tab and then the backslash
character
you can concatenate strings with the
plus operator you can see here that we
have two strings I come first and I come
second they've been added together or
concatenated with this so the are STR
our string is now one long string that
says I come first I come second I'll
give you another example here so we can
say my string equals this is the start
and then I'm going to put a space before
the in quotation mark because when these
get concatenated together we want there
to be a space between these two
sentences and I'll say this is the end
now let's just see what that looks like
I'll do a consult out log and do a my
string and let's see if I run this we
can see this is the start this is the
end just one long string
you could also concatenate strings using
the plus equal operator you can see here
in this example we have the AR string
equals I come first and then we have the
AR string plus equals I comes second
so remember just like in when you're
using numbers plus equals means that you
take whatever is on the end here and add
it to the variable so we've just added I
come second on to the end of I come
first let's do another example down here
my string equals this is the first
sentence and then I'll put a space at
the end because we're gonna do my string
and I'll hear oh I'll do the plus equals
this is the second sentence now if I
just do a console that log here of my
string we should see that those
sentences have gone together this is the
first sentence this is the second
sentence good
you can concatenate strings together
with variables you can see here our name
freako camp hello our name is and then
we add this variable the our name
variable which is freako camp hello our
name is freako camp how are you well
we're gonna do the same thing down here
so I'm gonna do my name equals o and
then my string is going to equal mine
name is and then I'm going to add the
variable name which is myname and then
I'll continue the string here hopes that
supposed to be a plus here and I am well
see that I put a space here and here
because you have to make sure you put
appropriate spaces in and let's see what
that looks like I'll do a consult out
log and I'll just put my string here if
I show that my name is Bo and I am well
looks good
you can append variables to strings with
this plus equals operator you can see
with this variable and adjective which
is set to the word awesome and then we
have another variable freako camp is and
we have the our string variable plus
equal an adjective so now our string is
going to equal freako camp is awesome so
let me show you another example we're
going to say some adjective equals worth
while and now I'm going to use the plus
equal so my STR plus equals and then I
can put some adjectives so now after we
do the my string plus equals some
adjective my string is going to say
learning to code is worthwhile
sometimes you want to find the length of
a string javascript makes this easy so
we have the first name is set to a de
but we just use the dot length property
to find the length so first name dot
length remember our first name is Ana
here and then dot length will return an
integer a number that has the number of
characters in the string so that will be
three so let's try this again here's
another example
last name length equals last name we
just have to type in dot length and just
to show you let me console that log that
and you'll be able to see if I put in
last name length and if I run that
you'll see eight because there are eight
characters in the word Lovelace
bracket notation is a way to get a
character at a specific index within a
string so you can see right here we have
the first name adda and right here we
have first name and then here's the
bracken notation you can see there's
brackets with a number inside so most
modern programming languages like
JavaScript don't start counting at one
like humans do they start at zero which
is called zero-based indexing so with
the number zero that refers to the in
the first index of this string which
would be the a so the a would be zero D
is one and then a is two so this first
letter of first name if we do first name