with a value of undefined so let's do
that we're gonna set an if statement if
a is less than zero or that's two pipes
B is less than zero then we're going to
return an undefined so we can do a test
here console.log eight but what if this
is a negative number it's going to
return undefined Skrim beheads a little
quirk here where it just shows null but
in a browser will show undefined
we are going to create a blackjack card
counting function so how how card
counting works at least how this
function is gonna work is that when you
see a low card that count goes up and
when you see a high card that count goes
down and if it's a middle value card the
count stays the same and then when the
count is positive the player should bet
high and when the count is zero or
negative the player should bet low so we
are going to use a switch statement to
figure out what card has been passed in
and what to do about it you can see that
the function looks like this see see and
we pass in a card and depending on what
the card is it's going to increase this
global count variable or it's going to
decrease it or it's going to stay the
same and then we are going to return two
things we're not gonna return changeme
we are going to return the current count
value and whether the player should hold
or bet so every time you call the CC
function it's going to change this count
value and return the total count so
let's see how this is going to work we
are going to use the switch statement
like I said and we're going to check the
card value that was passed in so if the
case is 2 3 4 5 6 we are going to
increment the count variable so we're
going to do like this case 2 I'm going
to do some copying and pasting if the
case is 2 3 4 5 6
well it just had to actually change
these values 3 4 5 6 now there are many
ways to write any program this could be
done with if statements and else
statements it could be even done with
other other ways that we haven't even
talked about yet as long as the program
works in this case that's all that
matters so if you find a different way
to write this program
that's great so if the case is two three
four five or six we are going to take
the account value and if we just do plus
plus that increments it by one and then
we're going to break now if the case is
seven eight nine so let's pay some three
of these blue seven eight nine actually
we're going to do nothing the account is
not going to change at all so we don't
even need case seven or eight nine so
instead of doing seven eight nine we
just need to check in the case that
something is actually going to happen so
we are going to decrement the count
variable if we have ten Jack queen king
or ace so that's what we're gonna change
this to ten Jack queen king or bass in
this case we're going to decrement the
count so you can do count - - so that's
the same as count equals count minus one
and then we will break now we've taken
care of the count and up game account
now we have to take care of what we're
going to return we are going to return
the count and we're also going to return
whether we are going to hold or bet so
we're going to actually return a
variable but first we're going to space
there's a space between the number and
then we're going to return the hold
variable now this is a variable we
haven't created yet normally this would
be the perfect time to use the ternary
operator but we haven't learned that yet
and what we're not going to learn that
for a few more lessons so I won't use
that now we are going to set what that
hold that value is first we'll create
the hold variable variable hold back and
we'll set it to
hold however if count is more than zero
then we can set hold that to equal that
so now this should work let's test it
out and see if we've made any mistakes
yet hold that is not defined well we
have it right here
hold Oh we spelled that wrong so instead
of halt bet that should we hold that
okay in this case we're going to bet
because we had a bunch of positive
numbers and then negative numbers but if
we change this to K I change this to 10
what do what happens now we're gonna
hold okay it worked
objects objects are similar to arrays
except that instead of using indexes to
access data you use properties so here's
an object called our dog objects are
going to be defined with these curly
braces before at the beginning of the
end and these are the properties now the
properties are everything before the
colons so we have name that's a property
legs the property and then the values
are the things after the colons here so
the name is camper the legs four tails
there's like one tail on this dog and
friends are everything now you can see
that with the properties can be strings
they can be numbers they can be arrays
they can be any data type in JavaScript
so now we are going to create our own
dog so this is going to have a name
personally I like the name Quincy so
we'll use that for our dog's name also
we're going to have legs unfortunately
our dog has had an accident he only has
three legs but to make up for the only
having three legs he does have two tails
and four friends another unfortunate
thing it's an empty array he has no
friends okay we've now created our own
object
there are two main ways to access a
property on an object the first I will
talk about is dot notation so we have
this test object and we have hat shirt
and shoes and we want to find out the
value of these properties so right here
the hat value we're gonna set a test
object now here's where we use the dot
notation we just put a dot or a period
and then I put the name of the property
about hat and then for the shirt value I
will do dot shirt so see this word right
here is just the word here so the value
of hat value test object that hat is now
gonna be ball cap and the value of the
shirt value is going to be jersey
besides using dot notation you can also
use bracket notation to access a
property and an object you can use
bracket notation anytime but it is
required if the name has a space in it
you can see in this object we have three
properties and each of them have a space
so to get the value of these properties
we're going to have to use bracket
notation so the entre value we're going
to test object that's the name of the
object and then we're gonna put brackets
kind of like an array index so you need
the opening and closing brackets and
inside we will put the name of the
property so I'll do a an entree and then
we can do it again down here for the
drink value and I'll I'll use a single
quote this happens have a double quote
to show that each of those will work the
drink and then we need the closing
brackets here so now Andre value is set
equal hamburger and drink value is set
to equal water
bracket notation can also be used to
look up object properties using
variables so here we have this test
object we have these different numbers
associated with these names here and we
are going to set this variable to be one
of the numbers so I'll set this to be 16
so now we can in this test object 16 is
Montana and we can look that up using
the variable name instead of the numbers
so instead of putting 16 I'm going to
put player number in here and now player
is set to the word the string Montana
and we use this variable to look up the
object property
we can use dot notation to update object
properties here you can see an object
called our dog it has a named legs tails
friends and the name is camper however
here we use dot notation our dog name
and use the assignment operator the
equal sign to set the name to happy
camper so if we did console dot log on
our dog name it would no longer be
camper it would be happy camper well we
have another dog here with a name of
coder but we want to change the name to
happy coder so that's what I'll do right
here so my dog dot name equals happy
coder so just like above we use dot
notation to set the object property to a
new value
you can add new properties to an object
using dot notation or bracket notation
so here's an example right here we have
this object our dog and there's four
properties here but down here we're
adding a new property our dog bark
equals bow-wow so it had four properties
but now it has five properties as the
property bark as well now down here
we'll add a property to the my dog
object so we can do my dog and then here
I'm going to use bracket notation set
dot notation bark I'm going to set that
to equal booth and because he's yelling
it will have an exclamation point and
that's how you add properties to objects
it's simple to delete a property from an
object our dog object has all these
properties and with the delete keyword
delete our dog bark so now this property
here the bark has been deleted and is no
longer in the object after we have
deleted it so we can do the same thing
down here and this time we will delete
the Hills property my dog that kills so
now the my dog object no longer has a
tails property
objects can be thought of as a key value
storage like a dictionary you can use an
object to look up values so in this case
we have a switch statement that returns
certain values so when you pass an alpha
to the function it returns Adams if you
pass in Bravo it returns Boston we can
replace this switch statement with an
object and use the object for lookups
instead of the switch statement let me
show you how that's done I'm going to
create var lookup this is going to be an
object here and the object is going to
have a bunch of key value pairs so we
have alpha and that's going to be Adams
and then we have Bravo and the value for
Bravo is going to be Boston and that's
it so we can now delete this whole
switch statement and now we can say
result equals lookup in bracket notation
we put the value that was passed in and
I forgot one thing which was the equal
sign here because lookup equals this
object and let's do a test so let me put
console dot log so we can actually see
what happens here so if we do charlie
we're gonna get Chicago if we do Foxtrot
the result will be Frank so it works
you can check if an object has a
property with the has owned property
method let me show you how to use this
method and finish making this function
where we check if an object has a
specific property if it doesn't have the
property will return not found so let me
show you how that's going to work we'll
do my abs that's the object up above
dock has owned dropped 40 and then we
pass in the property we're gonna check
which is check crop this is either gonna
come back as true or false if it has the
property so let's make this into an if
statement if my my object has own
property check crop but if that's true
we're going to return my ABS and then
use bracket notation check crop so go
we're going to return the value of that
property else we're going to return not
found so let's pick up this other return
statement and I'll do a test so when we
pass in gift here we returned pony but
let's say we passed in hello you load
that not found okay it works
a JavaScript object is a way to store
flexible data so you can store strings
numbers and arrays and even other
objects so in this example we have an
array called MyMusic we can see it's an
array because we have the open break and
closed bracket but inside the array are
objects so this is one of the objects
and inside the objects are all these key
value pairs with the strings and the
numbers and so on so I'm going to add
another object so since this is array
after each element in an array you have
a comma so I'm gonna add a comma here
and then I'm going to add my next record