你可以用 += 把变量转换成字符串
你可以看到这个变量 anAdjective，它的赋值是 awesome
然后我们有另一个变量 ourStr，赋值 freeCodeCamp is
用 += 将两个变量连接起来
现在 ourStr 变量的值就是 freeCodeCamp is awesome
另一个例子
我们定义变量 someAdjective 的值为 worthwhile
然后我们使用 +=
输入 myStr += someAdjective
myStr 的值就成为了 Learning to code is worthwhile
有时候你想要计算一个字符串的长度
用 JavaScript 代码很容易实现
变量 firstName 赋值为 Ada
我们使用 .length 属性确定长度
所以就是 firstName.length
记住 firstName 的值是 Ada
然后 .length 就会返回一个整数
也就是字符串中字母的数量
结果就是 3
我们再试一次
另一个例子
lastNameLength 等于 lastName
我们需要输入 .length
使用 console.log
输入 lastNameLength
点击运行
结果是 8
因为这个字符串 lovelace 有 8 个字母
bracket notation is a way to get a
character at a specific index within a
string so you can see right here we have
the first name adda and right here we
have first name and then here's the
bracken notation you can see there's
brackets with a number inside so most
modern programming languages like
JavaScript don't start counting at one
like humans do they start at zero which
is called zero-based indexing so with
the number zero that refers to the in
the first index of this string which
would be the a so the a would be zero D
is one and then a is two so this first
letter of first name if we do first name
with the bracket notation with a zero
that's gonna equal a so let me show you
another example let's say we want to get
the first letter of the last name again
I'm just gonna do the bracket notation
and put a zero here if I wanted the
second letter the oh I will put a 1 here
so if I console that log we can see what
it came up with so console that log
first letter of last name and if we look
in the console l because the first
letter of the last name is L
strings are immutable meaning they
cannot be altered once created this does
not mean that they cannot be changed
just that the individual characters of a
string literal cannot be changed so look
at this example my string and then we're
going to use bracket notation to choose
the first letter so it currently says
jello world we want the first letter to
change to an H to say hello world but if
I run that there's going to be an error
because of the immutability of strings
now we can still change this to hello
world but we can't just change an
individual letter like that so we're
gonna have to do my string equals and
I'm just gonna have to type in the whole
thing which is hello world and now it we
will change to the word hello world
you can use bracket notation to get any
character position in a string so
earlier we did the first position but
here's how you would get the second
position
remember the zero index so one is the
second position zero is the first
position we can also get the third
letter of the last name using the
brackets we'll just put two in the
brackets to get the third letter of the
last name
you can also use bracket notation to
find the last letter in a string even if
you don't know how many letters are on
the string you do it based on the length
so if you look right here in the
brackets we have a expression to be
evaluated first name dot length minus
one so the length is 3 3 minus 1 is 2
the reason why we're doing a minus 1 is
because remember we count starting at 0
so the length minus 1 is going to be the
last index of the name so we can do that
same thing here to get the last letter
of the last name I can just do last name
dot length minus 1 and that's going to
get the last letter of the last name
which is the e right here
we saw how to use bracket notation to
get the last letter of a string you can
also do the third to last letter or
fourth to last letter
so you just subtract however much you
want from the for the the length of the
string so we have the bracket notation
first name that length minus three
that's going to get the third to last
letter so we want the second-to-last
letter into this variable here we do
something similar we just do last name
dot length and then we're gonna subtract
two to get the second to last character
of the string
we are going to use our knowledge of
strings to build a mad libs style word
game in a mad lib game you are provided
sentences with some missing words like
nouns verbs adjectives and adverbs and
then you fill in the missing pieces with
words of your choice to make a sentence
that could be funny and hopefully makes
a little bit of sense so let me show you
how you do this
um this also uses a function now we
haven't talked about functions yet I'm
gonna explain those more later but
format for now just go with it because
that's not the point of this lesson for
now but this function called word blanks
you can call the function and you have
to pass in certain types of words you
pass in a noun an adjective a verb and
an adverb so down here you can see that
we're calling the function called word
blanks that's the function name here and
we're passing on a noun an adjective a
verb and an adverb so the point is that
we are going to use all these words that
are passed in to make a sentence so we
know that var result equals an empty
string at first and then we have to use
all these words and result and then the
result is going to be returned from this
function and eventually we'll be logged
out onto the screen with this console
dot log so what I'm gonna do here is do
result plus M equals we're gonna use the
plus equals to add something to this
result using all the noun the adjective
the verb and the adverb so let's see
it's gonna say the and we'll use the
adjective I adjective this case will be
the big a big and then let's put the
noun my noun because adjectives are
words that describe nouns a big
and then we're gonna say what this now
is doing the verb my verb the big dog
ran and then what where does he run to
to the store and then we're going to add
oh we need a space here so there's a
space between this to the store and then
we're going to add the final adverb so
now we have to add a period and there's
one more thing we have to add or a few
more things so right now it's my
adjective my noun my verb and there's no
spaces in between those so if I run that
you can see what that's gonna look like
in the console it just said big Don big
dog ran with no spaces so we're gonna
have to add some spaces in here also
let's do that now it's going to take in
the noun adjective verb an adverb and
then put it into that sentence so one
cool thing is we can actually pass in
some different words so like friends
let's if I copy this I'm going to paste
it instead of dog I will put for the
noun bike and an adjective
I'll put slow and then for the verb I'll
put flew and the adverb I'll put slowly
and now if we look in the console we
have to work two sentences the big dog
ran to the store quickly the slow bike
flew to the store slowly
arrays allow you to store several pieces
of data in one place so look at this
example our array now arrays always
start with a bracket and then end with a
bracket to show the beginning and ending
of the array and every element in the
array is separated by a comma
so you can see here we the first element
is a string the second element is a
number and you can have more and more
elements you just put comma and you can
keep adding elements and the elements
can be any data type you can see here we
have a string and a number but you can
always also use arrays or floating
numbers or really any sort of other data
type in your array so let's see another
example so let's do my array Quincy and
then for a number we'll do one because
Quincy is number one
when one of the elements in an array is
another array that's called a nested
array or a multi-dimensional array you
can see here's the beginning of the
array and here's end of the array but
the first element in this array is
another array with two elements of its
own same with here the second element is
an array so this is two arrays within
another array so we can do that here
here's another example
so let's our first element in the array
will be an array with a string and a
number and then I'll put a comma that
put the second element of the array
which will be another array with a
string and a number
earlier we learned how to use bracket
notation to find a specific index in a
string you can do the same thing with
arrays so look at this array our array
we have three elements 50 60 70 and
these have the indexes 0 1 2 so with
this our array with the bracket notation
in the 0 that's going to be index 1
which is going to equal 50 so we can do
the same thing here my array equals 50
60 70 so let's try to find the first
element that array so var are my data
equals my array and then I'm going to do
index 0 I could do index 1 index 2 and
then if we console dot log that we can
see for sure what that is so if I put my
data and we can see in the console it's
you can use array indexes to modify
arrays now we try to do this earlier
with strings using bracket notation and
we were not able to modify a string
using bracket notation but with arrays
you can so the original array is 1864 99
and then we're gonna use the array index
of 1 now 1 is going to be the second
number or 0 1 2 and this number 64 is
going to be set to 45 so the new array
is gonna be 1845 99 let's try it again
with this 1864 99 so let's do my array
and then instead of doing the first the
second digit I'm gonna do the first
digit and the array the first index
which would be index 0 and I will say
equals 45 so now this array has been
updated so if I do console that log and
then through my array will see that the
array is now 45 64 99
you can also use bracket notation to
select an element in a multi-dimensional
or array of arrays so you can see this
array here we have our outer array but
inside that array are more arrays the
elements of the array or other arrays
and the last element of the array
actually has an array in this so this is
a three-layer deep array right here so
to access an array of arrays or an
element within an array that's within an
array you use a double bracket notation
so if you see this example here my array
the first bracket is 0 that's gonna get
the first element in the array which
would be right here and then that
element is an array so the second
bracket would be the index of the array
within the array so this 0 will point to
here so let's try to figure out how we
can select a value equal to 8 well let's
see I see an eight right here so let's
figure out what this first number should
be well let's count 0 1 2 so the third
array would be index 2 now when you want
to go 0 1 now if you index 1 to get the
second number in the third array so
let's test to see if that equals 8 so
I'll do a consult out log and then do my
data here and we'll see if that equals 8