so we're gonna iterate through this loop
while I is more than 0 we're going to
keep iterating and at the end of each
iteration we're gonna decrement I
instead of increment it we're gonna go
down by 2 i minus equals 2 means i
equals I minus 2 so we're gonna continue
pushing the lower and lower numbers onto
the array until I is less than 0 so
let's log this out and see what our
array becomes you can see 10 8 6 4 2
well I'm gonna write another one where
we're gonna push the odd numbers from 9
through 1 to my I took the my array so
another for loop and I'm going to do VAR
I equals 9 because we want to start at 9
now we'll still do I is more than 0 so
while I is more than 0 we're gonna keep
going through this array and we'll do I
and we just everything else is really
the same - equals 2 and this is gonna
get all the odd numbers onto the array
so we just have to do my array dot push
and then push on the I there and I'll
just console that log so we can see what
it ended up as my array and I'll run the
code 9 7 5 3 1 we did it
it is common in JavaScript to iterate
through the contents of an array so look
at this example we have this array here
before we were are always adding items
to the array but this time the array
already exists right here our array 9 10
11 12 so we are going to start at 0 but
now instead of going to a specific
number of iterations we are going to the
our array dot length so the length is 4
here but if we added elements to this
array that means this loop would just go
even longer until we went through every
element of that array and then at the
end we're going to increment I by 1 at
the end of each iteration so look what
we're doing inside the array we're doing
our total that starts out at 0 up here
and we're doing plus equals that means
we're going to do our total equals our
total plus something else so we're gonna
keep adding to the total whatever is in
the array at that index so our array I
so it starts at 0 and then it goes 1 2 3
until it gets to 4 which is the length
of the array and it doesn't even run the
iteration at 4 and there is no index 4
on the array remember it's 0 1 2 3 so
this is just going to add up all those
numbers if we run this we can see it
adds up to 42 I'm gonna write another
for loop down here that's going to add
up all the numbers in this array here so
we'll do for our I equals 0 and then we
do I is less than my array dot length
and I plus plus so just like before for
each element in my array we're gonna do
a my we're going to do a total
plus equals my array index I so we have
to initialize the total variable right
up here so the VAR total equals zero and
then at the end we can just we'll just
console dot log that out to see what the
total is so if I just run this we can
see that the total this time is 20
if you have a multi-dimensional or
nested array you can use nested
for-loops to access all the array
elements so for instance we have this
multiply off function it's defined up
here but we're calling it here and we're
passing in this multi-dimensional array
which is basically an array with arrays
inside the array so inside the first
array there are three elements 1 2 3 and
you can see each of those elements are
an array with their own set of elements
so we are going to use nested for-loops
within this multiply all function to
multiply every number in these nested
arrays here so let's get started we're
going to start with a for loop and it's
going to look just like the other four
loops that we started I equals 0 we're
going to initialize I to 0 and then
we're gonna say while I is less than our
length and then we're just going to
increment I at the end of each iteration
now are that linked that's going to
start off as 3 because we're passing in
this array and the first level of the
array there's just 1 2 3 elements so
that's gonna be 3 but now we're gonna go
inside this for loop and create another
for loop so we're gonna do VAR J equals
0 normally its standard practice to call
the variable that we're incrementing I
but we already have an eye within this
scope so we need to create another name
and it's pretty standard to call the
next variable J because J is after I so
now we're gonna do J while J is less
than now this is where it gets a little
tricky we're gonna do while a is less
than our index I dot length also we're
gonna increment J here so this is going
to change so first the first iteration
of this outer for loop we're looking at
the length of this array then we're
linking looking at the length of this
array then we're looking at the length
of this array the index is going to be
different every time so we're going to
be going to each different
inside the nested array so at this point
we just have to multiply all the numbers
together so we already have the product
that we've defined above so we're gonna
do product x equals which is just gonna
multiply everything together and we're
going to do our eye Hey so the eye
references the outer array and the J
references the inner array within the
what we're passing in and now we're done
so let's we have the console dot log
here so let's run this and see what
happens and 5040
next I'm going to talk about do-while
loops now we already talked about while
loops and I'm gonna review this while
loop and then I will tell you how a
do-while loop is different than a while
loop so this while loop first checks the
condition before it runs any code within
the loop a do while loop will always run
at least one time and then it will check
the condition so here we have this empty
array we have I equals 10 so while I is
less than 5 well I is not less than 5 so
it's not gonna do anything let's see
what happens so we see it logged out 10
and then an empty array because I
started as 10 and my array started as
this empty erase you were logging the I
and my array with a do-while loop it's
different so what I'm going to do is cut
this line up here and put it at the end
and then at the beginning I'm gonna put
the keyword do in a do-while loop this
is always run at least once before it
checks the condition so first it's going
to do these things and then it's going
to check the condition in this case it's
going to find out the condition as false
and it's going to break out of the loop
let's see what happens here
see now I is 11 and the array has the 10
added to it
this is a coding challenge we have this
array of objects in our context lists
and you'll see each object is one of our
contacts with the first name a last name
a number and likes so these are key
value pairs here so what we want to do
is create this lookup profile function
where we pass in a name this is a first
name and the property and it's going to
return the value of that property for
instance if we pass in the name christen
here and we pass in the property of a
number it should return unknown if we
pass in the first name of Sherlock up
here and we return the property and we
pass in the property of likes it should
return the array intriguing cases and
violin if the name that's passed in does
not correspond to any context then our
functions to return no such contact and
if there's no property it should return
no such property so let's go to this
function here and start creating it so
the first thing we're going to have to
do is iterate through each element in
the contacts list so let's make a for
loop so for bar VAR I equals 0
while I is less than contacts length and
at the end of each iteration we'll do i
+ + to increment that so for each of
these contacts the first thing we're
going to check is if the name is a name
in this list so if contacts I
first name equals equals equals the name
that was passed in so we're checking
each eye to see if was the name that was
passed in and if so we're going to do
something now if now we're gonna do
something else so let's do that now
remember if the name that was passed in
is not in the array we're going to
return no such contact however if it is
in the array we're gonna do something
else if the name is in the context list
we're going to return the value of the
property that was passed in so return
contacts
I dropped so this will return the value
of that property that was passed in
however there is another case which is
if the property does not exist we return
no such property so a fancy way in
JavaScript of saying use this value if
it exists but otherwise use a different
value is to use the or operator
so we'll say return contact I prop or if
it doesn't exist we're gonna return no
such property and just so you know there
would be a way to do this without using
this or operator as long as that your
code passes the requirements that's all
that's important
there's many ways of doing this but
let's check it so right now we have our
lookup profile we're passing a Maki row
and we're trying to find the likes and
we're constantly logging the data and
pizza coding brownie points so what if
we passed in something else if we passed
in Sherlock a pass in last name
contact well that's working because I
spelled Sherlock wrong this is e so it's
good the way a good way to test that
Holmes and the last thing we'll check is
if we pass in a property that does not
exist I'll just say hello and no such
property so our function works
there is a simple way to create a random
decimal number in JavaScript it's with
the math dot random function so we have
this function here which is says random
function and it's returning zero
currently but we're gonna use the math
dot random function and you will see
that when I run this we have zero point
two three eight one three seven four one
and so on so it's always going to be a
number between zero and it could be zero
between zero and one but it could not be
one
often you want a random hole number
instead of a random decimal number that
can be accomplished with math dot floor
we have mat that floor here this rounds
down to the nearest whole number so we
pass in math dot random times 20 and
then we round down to the nearest whole
number this is going to create a random
whole number between 0 and 19 remember
math dot random can never be 1 it can be
0 but it can never be quite 1 so when we
multiply it by 20 we are going to get a
number between 0 and 20 but not
including 20 then we round down which
will end up being 0 to 19 so let me show
you another example where we're going to
get a random whole number between 0 &amp; 9
it looks just like this so we're going
to modify this function so this math dot
random we're going to pass that into
math.floor so I have to put the
parentheses because we're passing it in
to that function and it's math dot
random times 10 and that's going to give
us a random number between 0 &amp; 9 so if I
reload this you can see 9 5 4 1 every
time I load it it's a different random
number
you can also generate random whole
numbers within a range so look at this
function here our random range it takes
a minimum number and a maximum number
and then it just runs through this
calculation here so we have the math dot
random and we multiply it by the max
number minus the min number plus 1 and
then we get the floor which is rounding
down and we add all that to our minimum
number so this is just a calculation to
get a random number between the min and
Max so as practice I'm going to rewrite
it down here so we have the random range
and instead of our men and our max we
have my men and my max however the
equation is going to be the same so we
have math dot floor you can take a
chance to actually just look over the
equation and see if you can understand
how it works my max - my men and then we
just have to do plus one and then this
whole thing is going to be plus my men
so we already have this example test set
up down here random range between 5 and
15 and we're going to log it out here so
let's try that 11 6 7 see every number
is between 5 and 15 whenever I run it
another useful function is the parse int
function it takes a string and returns
an integer a lot of times you want to
make sure you're dealing with integers
and not strings for different
calculations and things like that
if the string cannot be converted into
an integer it returns in a in for not a
number so let me show you how it works
from this convert to integer function we
are going to return and we're going to
return the string except we're going to
convert it into an integer first so
we'll do parse int and then I'll pass in
the string now it was a string because
you can see here we're passing in the
string of the 56 but it's going to
return it as a number and integer
the person function can also be used
with a radix the radix specifies the
base of the number in the string such as
base 2 or base 7 or base 8 a base 2
would be binary so that's one of the
most common ones to use now the default
is base 10
that's what we use normally every day
but let me show you how that would work
we're gonna convert this number which is
a binary number to an integer so we'll
do return and I will do the parse and
I'll pass in this string as before but
now we'll have a second argument after
the comma which is going to be the
number 2 so and so the default of base
10 will be passing it as base 2 so the
computer knows that this is a binary
number
I love the ternary operator it's like a
one-line if-else expression now this is
what it looks like you have your
condition just like in an if statement
and then you would have a question mark
after the question mark you have what's
gonna happen if the condition is true
then you have a colon then you have
what's going to happen if the condition
is false so we can replace an if-else
statement like this into something using
the ternary operator so here we have
this if this condition is true we're
going to return true else we're going to
return false let's change this so now
we're going to use the ternary operator
so now it's just going to say return a
equals equals B that's the condition
then we use the question mark so if it's
true we're going to return true and then
we've have a colon and after the colon
we have what's going to happen if it's
false which is we're going to return
false
now I'm we honest you would never write
a line like this in real life because
you could just write return a equals
equals equals B and this lines actually
going to do the same thing as this line
however I just wanted to give you a
simple example of using the ternary
operator
one of the great things about
conditional or ternary operators is that
you can nest them within each other
which gives them even more power so
we're going to read write a function
here the function check sign and it's
going to return the string positive if
this number is positive negative if if
the number is negative or zero and we're
gonna use a nested conditional operator
so here it is return and first we're
going to check if num is more than zero
and then we'll use the ternary operator
if so the first thing after the question
mark is if it's true if it's true we're
gonna return positive if it's false if
the number is not more than zero we'll
do something else but here's where we're
going to have another ternary operator
we're gonna check if num is less than
zero so if the number is less than zero
well if that's true we have to have the
question mark for the ternary operator
if that's true we're going to return
negative and if it's false that's where
the colon comes in we're going to return
zero so let's do this check sign I'm
going to do a console about log so we
can see what this returns here and we
can see this is going to return positive
if we have a negative number here it's
going to return negative or if we have a
zero it's going to return zero now
you'll see that after this :
we have an entire ternary operator so if
this is true we just return positive if
it's false then we do everything here
which is another ternary operator where
it checks if this is true and if that's
true we return negative and if it's
false we to return zero
for a long time in JavaScript if you
were going to declare a variable you had
to use the VAR keyword but starting with
es6 in 2015 we can now declare variables
with let and Const as well over the next
few lessons I will be talking about what
let and constitute that it's different
than var but one of the things is that
let does not let you declare a variable
twice so let's look at this example we
have var cat name equals Quincy and then
down here var cat name equals Bo and if
I just run this code you'll see that
nothing is happening it's just allowing
us to set the cat name twice and to
clear it twice with the VAR keyword
however if we change this to let we're
gonna change all the var to let and
you'll see that when we load it again
you'll see an error
duplicate declaration cat name so this
is good that's creating this error
because you usually don't want to
declare a variable two times in the same
scope so this allows your program to
give you an error to tell you that
you've done something wrong now you can
still reset it so if we didn't use the
word let here we could just set the cat
name variable and now we're not gonna
get an error in this case we're
declaring the variable here to be Quincy
and we're setting the same variable to a
new name here this is one of the few
reasons that many people only use Latin
Const and never use var to declare
variables another thing in this code you
can see is use strict now this enables
strict mode which caches common coding
mistakes and unsafe actions so a lot of
people will use use strict at the top of
a full JavaScript file or maybe just in
a function to catch coding mistakes such
as if you create a variable and don't
declare it with varla a Const
another major difference between the var
and let keywords is that when you
declare a variable with var it is
declared globally or locally if declared
inside a function however let the scope
of let is limited to the block statement
or expression that it was declared in so
let's look at this example here if you
see this code we have this check scoped
function and we're calling it down here
and it's setting I with a var here of
our keyword - function scope then we're
setting it to block scope in here and
you can see it's console that logging
block scope eye is it says block scope
and we will get down here function scope
it's still block scope if we want this
to be function scope down here we're
going to have to use let so we would use
let here and then we would use let here
and if we run the code now you can see
in the console block scope eye is block
scope function scope eye is function
scope so even though we set I to block
scope here inside this block now a block
is just anything inside these squiggly
braces here so we set I inside this
block to block scope but then when we
get out here it's now back to function
scope because of this up here here's
another thing I want to show you if this
is if we comment this line out and we
change this to var what do you think is
gonna happen
well let's run and find out look we set
the var inside this block here to block
scope and it says block scope is block
scope but then when we're outside of the
block when we're outside of these
squiggly braces here we can still access
I here and it set the block scope but if
this was a let and we're declaring
inside this block if we run that now
when we get outside the block we get an
error because it's not defined
so that's another reason why people use
let instead of var is so that they can
make sure the variable is only defined
in the area they want to be defined in
but for now I'll uncomment this out
const is another way to declare a
variable it has all the features of left
but it's also read-only
you cannot reassign a Const so let's
look at this program here we're running
this print many times and it's going to
log out this sentence and the sentence
is up here vard sentence is declared and
then we reassign it here so first we
declare this sentence to be the string
is cool then it's reassigned to be the
string it's amazing so if we run that it
should work it prints free code camp is
amazing many times but if we change this
to Const let's see what happens
now I'll run this and we get an error
sentence is read only if you declare a
variable with the Const keyword you
cannot reassign it afterwards this can
be very helpful to prevent you from
accidentally making mistakes later if
you know for sure that you never want to
reassign a variable always use Const so
you don't accidentally reassign it when
you don't mean to another thing is when
you're using Const it's very common to
use all capital letters so like this
sentence like that and that's another
way to remember that it's a constant so
if I rename this year I'm also going to
have to repeat it here and while we're
at it we're gonna change this to left
because for the most part you should
only use Const or let but there are
certain circumstances where you would
use var and also in some other videos in
this course I'll be using var but in
your own code you should mainly use
Const and let let's reload this to see
what happens and it worked free code
camp is cool many times we can no longer
say that free code camp is awesome even
though we know it actually is
while you cannot reassign a variable
declared with Const you can mutate an
array so look at this example that's not
gonna work
first we declare the variable s and we
assign it to an array we declare with
Const and now we're gonna reassign the
variable s here but if we do that we're
gonna get the air s is read-only however
we can update the array using bracket
notation so I'll just comment that out
and using bracket notation I'll do index
0 I'll assign that to to index 1 I'll
assign that to 5 and then index 2 I'll
assign that to 7 and just like that it
is going to reassign the array so if I
just do a console dot log here console
dot log and put the array in there we
should see the new array here 2 5 7
as seen previously a Const declaration
alone doesn't really protect your data
from mutation if you have an object or
an array you can still mutate it even if
it's declared with Const there is
something called object dot freeze that
will prevent data mutation so let me
talk to you about object dot freeze
first of all let's understand this
function here we're using this function
to demonstrate object dot freeze so it's
going to create this constant math
constants with the PI in it this is an
object and right now this can still be
changed so if we look down here this is
a try-catch block will talk about
try-catch blocks in more detail later
but for now you just have to know that
it's going to try what's in the first
part of the block and if there's an
error then it's going to go into the
catch part and it's going to log it out
so right now we're going to try to
change math constants that pi to 99 and
if you can see right here we're going to
return the math that constants that pi
and down here we are doing into a
variable called pi so if we run this
you'll see that we console that log time
it's 99 but wait a second we don't want
pi to change because we know that pi
never changes that's why we're gonna use
object dot freeze so I'll put it right
here I'm gonna do object not freeze and
then in parentheses I'll put the object
which is math constants now I've frozen
math constants so when it tries to
change math constants top pi here it's
not going to work and it's going to go
into this catch block and it's going to
log out the ear or the exception so let
me run that and you'll see type air
cannot assign to read only probably a PI
of object so we had an error and we can
see here that pi is stays the same at
3.1
or so whenever you have an object and
you don't want any of the items in the
object to change use object dot freeze
this function here is called an
anonymous function it doesn't have a
name it is assigned to this variable
magic but there's no word right before
the function keyword to assign the name
to the function whenever you have an
anonymous function you can convert it
into an arrow function that makes it a
little quicker to write so instead of
the word function I'm going to take that
out completely and then put an arrow
here so this is the same thing except
it's just a little quicker to write but
we can shorten this even more if we're
just returning one value here we don't
even need the return keyword and we
don't need the curly braces so I can