right below this comment here and we are
going to have just like well above we're
gonna have an artist the artist is going
to be Bo Carnes and then we have a title
the title will be a serial man the
release year will be 2003 and for
formats this is going to be an array
it's just like above so we can have any
format I'm gonna put YouTube video and
now we've created a second object in our
in our my music array and each objects
hold data in a property which is the key
value format this is very similar to
JSON which we will talk more about later
here we have an object with other
objects nested inside that so in order
to access sub properties of an object
you can chain together the dot or
bracket notation so I'm trying to get
the glove box contents so I'm going to
take away this undefined here and I'll
do my storage dot car dot inside and
then now the next thing it's it with a
car inside the last thing is glove box
because there's a space here we have to
use bracket a shin so I'm gonna use
bracket notation on the end here and say
glove box and now if we run this C we
are going to console that lock so let's
see if we get the contents here yep Maps
it worked
arrey bracket notation
to access nested arrays you can see we
have this array here and inside this
array are two objects the first elm and
the array is this object the second elm
and array is this object and then inside
the object we have a key value pair the
key is less and the value is another
array here so we can combine dot
notation and bracket notation to access
the second tree that's what we're trying
to do here so let's do that first we
need to do my plants and the trees are
the second element in the my plant array
which is index one now we need to get
though the list so the list of trees
here so I'm going to do dot lists and
since that list is an array I can use
the bracket notation to get the the
second list element which again is array
index one so if we run this it's going
to console that log and we see pine
that's the second tree here
this is a coding challenge we're gonna
do we're giving given this object here
which is a record collection each record
has an ID and then it also has different
pieces of information about the record
they don't all have the same information
but see we have art album artist tracks
album artist tracks this just says
artist tracks and this just has album
here and we are supposed to create this
update records function where we can
pass in the ID the property and the
value and it's going to update our
record collection with the property of
the value so for instance if we pass in
the ID
2468 and we put the property artists and
if we set a different value like Quincy
or something like that then we should
update this whole object so now it says
Quincy instead of prints and we should
return the full collection so it's going
to update the collection and then return
the collection if we have an empty
string for the value it should just
completely delete that property also if
we have the property of tracks and then
we have a value instead of updating the
whole tracks here with what we put in
it's just going to add the track to the
end of this array so if you look right
here it says the comment says keep a
copy of the collection for tests this
JSON dot parse and json dot stringify
and then collection this is just a fancy
way in JavaScript to make a copy of the
object remember in our function we are
going to be changing the collection
object but we want to have a copy of the
original object before anything was
changed so that's what that's for so
let's go ahead and do that so we're just
updating this function here this update
records function okay so let's get to
this so we'll do if value
equals equals equals blank because the
first condition we are going to test for
is if we need to delete the property
remember if the value is at the blank we
delete that property so if the value is
blank we are going to delete election
and then we have to use bracket n ID and
then try the collection ID crop that's
the collection here if we pass in the ID
1248 it will go to there the property if
we passed an album for the property will
go to here and then we'll just delete
that whole thing if our values in the
empty string okay the next condition we
have to look for is if the property is
tracks because for most properties we're
just going to override that property
with the value passed into the function
but if the property is tracks we are
going to push on to the end of the array
so let's do an else if else if prop
equals equals equals tracks then we just
have to push on to the end of the array
so there's also another condition here
which is if the tracks property is empty
if the tracks property is empty we need
to create it here's a fancy way to do
that collection ID props so if prop
equals tracks we are going to set the
tracks because we're prop is going to
equal track we're going to set the
tracks to equal it's going to either
equal itself if it exists or if it
doesn't exist we're going to create it
I'll show you how collection ID huh it's
gonna equal itself or that's the or
operator it's going to equal an empty
array so if this already exists we're
gonna set to equal itself but if itself
doesn't exist
we'll just set it to equal and empty
array so that's just a way to create
that property if it doesn't already
exist so now that we know it exists we
can just push the value to the end of
the array
collection ID prop and we'll just do the
dot push and then put in the parentheses
the value so we're able to push the
value that was passed into this function
onto the end of the array okay there's
only one last condition which is the
just kind of the default condition else
so if the values in blank and the
property isn't tracks then we just push
the value onto the property then we just
set the property to equal the value just
like this collection ID prop equals
value okay let's test this out so we
already have this example down here but
to see if it actually worked we're going
to do a consult log so we can see the
output there and if I run that I'll let
me open up the console so I can really
see it so let's see what we changed go
to 5 4 3 9 and we set the artist which
didn't previously exist to ABBA
so let's look down here in the console 5
4 3 9 and the artist is ABBA
let's see what happens when we add a
track so we'll do one more example here
I'll just put right above here 8 records
and I'm going to pass in something I'll
pass in let's see the ID 2 4 6 8 and
we'll pass in the key which is going to
be tracks and then for the value
we'll put test
so let's see what happens here if we run
that it's gonna update the record here
and that's gonna update the record again
but we don't care about that one we may
like hear that it's gonna console that
log what the final value is so if we
look at 2 4 6 8 here 2 4 6 8 let's see
the tracks we at 1999 little red
Corvette and test so it's working great
loop's allow you to run the same code
multiple times I'm going to talk to you
about a while loop that runs while a
specified condition is true and stops
once it's no longer true so we are going
to push the digit 0 through 4 on to this
array here's how it's going to work
while it's a while loop while I is less
than 5 and we're gonna do something
while that's true first with a set where
I I starts off at at so var I equals 0
so while I is less m 5 will do my array
push hi just push it onto the array and
to make sure this loop eventually ends
I'll have to do I plus plus which
increments I so then I will test this
out by doing console dot log and I'm
gonna console that log to my array so
let's see if this works I'll run this
and check the console 0 1 2 3 4 the
while loop worked every time we went
through this five different times and
pushed 0 1 2 3 &amp; 4 onto the loop
a for-loop is the most common type of
loop in JavaScript so here is an example
of a for loop you start with the keyword
for and then we have these parentheses
with three different items and they're
separated by semicolons the first thing
is the initialization then we have the
condition then we have the final
expression so the initialization happens
before any of the code inside the loop
runs so we will start by initializing I
to equal 0 so this is what most for
loops start with is you have a variable
that you're going to initialize for the
for loop then the next thing is the
condition so once this evaluates to
false we break out of the loop so while
I is less than 5 we'll continue to run
through the loop over and over until
this is false and we break out of the
loop the final thing is what we do at
the end of each iteration at the end of
each iteration we will increment I by 1
in this example we are filling our array
with the numbers 0 through 4 I'm going
to do another example where we fill an
array with the numbers 1 through 5 so
we'll start with for now we're gonna
initialize I to equal 1 we're starting
with 1 instead of 0 this time and we're
gonna do I is less than 6 so while I is
less than 6 or until I is more than 6 we
are going to run all the code in this
loop and at the end of each iteration we
are going to increment I now I can just
do what we have before my array dot push
hi so the final thing we will do is test
this I will do console dot log and put
my array inside here and I'll just load
this and see what we see in the console
1 2 3 4 5 it worked we iterated 5
different times and each time we pushed
a new digit on to the array and at the
end of each iteration we incremented I
so
it pushed a larger number onto the array
loop's don't just have to increment one
at a time
look at this for loop here we have our
initialization where we initialize I to
0 and then we are going to run the loop
until I is less than 10 and finally
there are increment instead of
incrementing I by 1 we're incrementing I
by 2 so now this is going to push all
the even numbers onto the array we have
console dot log so let's log it out and
see what it looks like 0 2 4 6 8 I'm
going to write another loop right now
that creates an array of odd numbers so
let's do that for VAR i equals 1 we'll
start at 1 while I is less than 10
I can use 10 again I'm gonna do I plus
equal to so we're still going to skip
count by twos but since we're starting
at 1 instead of 0 this should give us
the odd numbers so let's see what's
gonna be inside our loop my array dot
plush and I'll just put I there so let's
log this out and see if we did it right
console dot log my array and I'll run
that 1 3 5 7 9 it worked
a for-loop can also be used to count
backwards so if we see this for loop
here we're initializing I to 10 we're
starting at 10 and we're going back to 0