you can append data to the end of an
array with the push function so see an
array has been set up here our array
Stimpson J cat and then we take our
array right here and use the push
function to push into the next Elm in
the array another array here so now it's
going to look like this we can see at
the end of the original array we've
pushed this other array at the end so
let's try it again down here we have my
array and you can see what we have
each Elm in the array is another array
so I am going to do my array dot push
and then I can push something on the end
here which will be like above another
array so this is gonna say dog I'm a 3
and now we've pushed this on to the
array
we can remove an item from an array with
the pop function here so see this pop
here and then we know it's a function
because of the parentheses at the end of
the word pop so the array starts with
one two three so now we do this our
array dot pop and it's going to return
the it's going to remove the last
element which is the three and then it's
gonna put it right into this variable
here so now as you can see down here
remove from our array now equals three
and then our array is gonna equal one
two because the three has been popped
off so we can do the same thing here so
remove from my array equals and I'm
going to do my array dot pop and we can
see what the array is gonna equal now if
I just do console dot log I array and if
you do this we can see that the array
only has the one item the one array
instead of the two arrays
the shift function is very similar to
the pop function except it removes the
first element of the array instead of
the final element so we see the shift
function on the end of the array here
and the array is the same as before but
now the first element Stimpson is being
removed as we shift off the first
element the array is going to equal J
cat and the removed from our array is
gonna equal Stimpson so let's do another
example down here we're gonna do a shift
again so I'm gonna do equals my array
shift and now my array is just going to
equal dog 3 and the remove from my array
is going to equal John 23
the unshifted is similar to the push
array function while push adds an
element to the end of the array on shift
adds an element to the beginning of the
array so let's look through this example
code we have the array Stimpson J cat
we're going to shift off the first
element remove the first element so our
array is J cat now we're gonna unshifted
an element at the beginning which is the
string happy so the array will now be
happy
J can't so let's try again this time the
array is john xxiii dog 3 because of the
shift we've shifted off the John 23 and
now I'm going to unshifted on shift now
we're going to add something to the
beginning of the array we'll do Paul
35 so now the array is this going to be
Paul 35 dog 3
let me give you another example of
nested arrays this will be a shopping
list so inside this array we're going to
have another array and we're gonna have
items cereal how many boxes three boxes
we also need some milk let's get two
cartons of milk let's get some bananas
three bunches of three bananas we'll
also get some juice two containers of
juice and finally we will get some eggs
we'll get 12 eggs and now we've created
an array of arrays which is our shopping
list
functions allow us to create reusable
code in JavaScript this is how a
function is set up we have the word
function then we have the function name
there's always parentheses here and you
can pass information into the
parentheses we'll talk about that later
and then we have these curly brackets so
that this is the opening curly bracket
and then we have the closing curly
bracket and everything inside the curly
bracket is run anytime the function is
called or invoked so here the function
is being called by just putting the
function name with parentheses after the
name so every time this function is
called just like this the console is
gonna say hey a world so if we load the
console right now you can see it says
hey a world and if I just copy this and
paste a few times we'll see that it's
going to say hey world hey world hey
world in the console since we have run
the function three times we see the
words hey a world three times so now I'm
going to create my own function that's
going to be very similar
so the function be usable function and
this time it's gonna say something
slightly different it's going to say hi
world
it's the heya world and now I can call
the function down here just like this
reusable function oh forgot to put the
parenthesis that's important
nice hey world and hi world in the
console
parameters are variables that act as
placeholders for the values that are to
be input to a function when it is called
so we have defined a function right here
called our function with arms and inside
the parenthesis we see the letters A and
B now these can be any name that we
could call these anything not just a and
B they could really be any words up here
and that means that when this function
is called we're going to pass data into
the function or input data into the
function so you can see the example here
where we're calling the function and
instead of saying a and B in the
parenthesis we're actually passing the
values 10 and 5 so when the function
runs it can use the information that's
passed into the function so in this case
it says console dot log a minus B well
that's going to be 10 minus 5 because
the numbers 10 and 5 have been passed
into the function and that's going to
output 5 so I'm going to create a
function that's very similar to that
function this one is going to be called
function with Arg
and it's also going to accept an A and B
but we could call that anything we want
and inside instead of subtracting a
minus B we're going to do a plus B now
I'm just going to call this function
function with our and I'll pass in 10
and 5 and let's see what that looks like
in the console so first it output 5 for
this one then an output a 10 for this
one
scope refers to the visibility of
variables variables which are defined
outside of a function block have global
scope global scope means they can be
seen everywhere in your JavaScript code
for instance I'm going to declare a
variable right here called my global
I'll set it to 10 now since this is set
outside of a function we can see it
anywhere in the whole code even in this
function right here called fun too we
can see that we reference it here and
here and what we're gonna be able to see
it now this is an if statement which we
will talk more about later but we're
checking if the type of my global does
not equal undefined so it will not equal
undefined if it has been defined and the
program knows about the variable since
this is global scope it does not equal
undefined equals 10 the program knows
about the variable because this is in
global scope so since this function can
access the my global variable will run
what's in this if statement where we
just add to this output variable my
global and then we put with the value of
my global which is 10 now here's another
example where we're gonna see if if the
type of oops global equals undefined
well we're gonna set that here so it is
possible to set a variable without using
the VAR keyword so I'm gonna set this to
loop global equals 5 so you can see here
that there is no var keyword so normally
if you do use a var keyword since this
is within a function it will be scoped
to that function if we have the VAR
keyword here this will be scoped to
function so you would not be able to see
it in this function however since we
forgot to put the VAR keyword in this
example there's no VAR keyword it
becomes global automatically that means
you can access it anywhere else in the
program including here so if we put the
VAR keyword then oops global would equal
undefined and then we would never have
this line in the output however since we
did not put the VAR keyword
oops global equals 5 and this will be
added to the output
oops global and then the : 5 so when we
console dot log the output it's going to
say my global 10 oops Global 5 now
actually it's not going to say that
because this is in scrim ba' and in
scrim but it's it's more careful and
just enforces the fact that you have to
use a VAR keyword but if we were in our
browser it would not enforce the VAR
keyword and then it would actually show
my global 10 oops global 5 if this was a
little complicated don't worry about
that because a lot of these concepts
will be going over again later with
additional examples
variables which are declared within a
function as well as the function
parameters have local scope that means
they are only visible from within the
function let me show you what I mean if
I declare a variable right here my var
equals five so we've declared this
variable inside a function so this
variable my var is only visible inside
the function so it says console that
logged my var it should console that log
to five so we're gonna call the function
here and it's gonna console dialogue my
var but then the program is gonna run
this console dot log that's outside of
the function it's still going to try to
access my var and so let's see what
happens you can see in the console that
first there's a five because it console
dot log within the function then there's
an error because it tried to access my
var outside of the function so really we
just need to delete this where we try to
access the variable outside the function
and now there is no error
it is possible to have both local and
global variables with the same name when
you do this the local variable takes
precedence over the global variable let
me show you an example here we have a
function called my outfit that's going
to return outerwear that's this variable
up here this is a global variable
because it is declared outside of the
function so when we console that log the
output of the my outfit function or the
my outfit function is going to return
outerwear which is the war t-shirt so
let's check the console and you can see
yep
t-shirt is there however let's change
this up a bit so we have some space here
because I'm going to put var outerwear
equals sweater so now if I run this
program you can see in the console it's
going to say sweater instead of t-shirt
it's because this local variable
outerwear took precedence over the
global variable another thing
interesting thing about this if I do
console.log and I console that log that
outerwear variable we'll see that it's
still t-shirt so first you see in the
console says sweater and t-shirt so
first we console dot log this function
which is sweater
it returns sweater and then we console
that log the global variable which is
t-shirt
you can return a value from a function
with this return statement so we have
this function here and we are passing a
number into it the num and then it's
going to return whatever's after the
return keyword in this case num minus 7
so here we're going to consult out log
the function and it returns the result
of minus 7 is this 10 minus 7 which is 3
so it's going to cancel that log the
number 3 if we look in the console yep
it
console.log the number 3 because the
function returns 3 let's try creating
another one this function is going to be
called times 5 again we'll pass in a
number and it's just going to return
something it's going to return the num
times 5 and then just like before we can
test it using a console dot log times 5
and we'll pass in the number 5 here and
if I run this we'll see that it returns
number 25
functions can have return statements but
they don't have to in this case this
function adds three to the sum variable
which is a global variable because it's
defined before the function it does not
return anything so if you don't specify
a return value the return value is just
undefined now I'm going to create
another function that is similar this
one is going to copy called add five and
this time we'll just do some equals sum
plus five or we can shorten this to use
the plus equals two now that's going to
add 5 to sum also but it's not going to
return anything so if we log this out it
would be undefined
it's simple to assign a returned value
to a variable see right here we have the
function change and you pass the number
and it's going to return the result of
this mathematical expression so when we
call the function change and pass in the
10 the value that is returned from this
function is won't be stored in this
variable here we can do the same thing
down here first we initialize the
variable processed and process arrgh
it's going to return the result of this
mathematical expression so I can set
processed to equal what this function
returns so I can say processed argh and
then I'll just pass in the number 7 here
and now process
equals the result of this mathematical
expression
in computer science a queue is an
abstract data structure where items are
kept in order new items can be added to
the back of the queue and old items are
taken off from the front of the queue
we're going to simulate that right now
some of the functionality of a queue
using this next inline function so the
purpose of this is to show that in this
next inline function you can add an item
to the array that's passed in and then
it's going to return the first item on
the list for instance if we have this
array right here if we add them at an
item to this array it should come after
at the end so it should come after five
and then it should return the first item
on the list in this case it's one so you
see we have some console dot log set up
so it should show what the list looks
like the array looks like beforehand and
then show what it looks like afterwards
this JSON dot stringify is just a way to
change an array into a string that can
easily be printed out to the screen so
to do this we're just going to have to
do two things that we've learned about
already so the first thing is to add the
item onto the list so we see right here
next in line passed in the test array
and six so we're calling this function
next on line we're passing in this test
in this test
array here and the number six we want